- Are you ready, kids?
- 孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- I can't hear you.
- 我听不到你说话。
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- * Ohh...
- * 哦...
* Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? *
*谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ *
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he *
- * 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的*
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * If nautical nonsense
be something you wish *
- *如果航海废话
成为你所希望的*
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish *
- * 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通 *
all: SpongeBob SquarePants!
- Ready?
所有：海绵宝宝！
- 准备好？
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob SquarePants!
- SpongeBob
- 海绵宝宝
SquarePants!
方裤！
[laughing]
[笑]
*
[waves crashing]
[海浪拍打]
- Ooh!
- 哦！
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
*
[line trilling]
[行颤音]
[car lock beeps]
[车锁蜂鸣声]
[indistinct conversations]
[模糊的对话]
- Hi, Pearl.
- Hey, girl!
- 嗨，珍珠。
- 嘿，女孩！
Let's hang out!
- Ugh, I can't.
我们出去玩吧！
- 呃，我不能。
I have to work
at Hot Dog on a String today.
我必须工作
今天在串热狗。
Brad called in sick, so I'm
in charge of stringing the dogs.
布拉德请了病假，所以我
负责给狗串绳。
Totally lame.
完全蹩脚。
- I guess
I'll see you later then.
- 我猜
那我稍后见。
- Uh...
- 呃...
Can I get one with,
uh, extra string?
我可以买一个吗
呃，额外的绳子？
- Ugh.
- 呃。
[heavy metal guitar tones]
[重金属吉他音色]
[phone screaming]
[电话尖叫声]
- What?
- Hey, girl!
- 什么？
- 嘿，女孩！
Want to come over and make fun
of boys or something?
想过来玩玩
男孩什么的？
- Uh, sorry, girl,
I can't.
- 呃，对不起，女孩，
我不能。
I'm working at Scorched Coral
all day.
我在焦珊瑚工作
一整天。
It's heinous.
真是令人发指。
- Oh!
[laughs]
- 哦！
[笑]
So heinous.
See ya later.
太令人发指了。
稍后见。
- See ya later, Pearl.
- 再见，珀尔。
- How much is this choker?
- 这个颈链多少钱？
- Um, it's a wrist band.
- 嗯，这是一个腕带。
- [gasping and choking]
- [喘气和窒息]
- Awesome.
- 惊人的。
[light instrumental music]
[轻音乐]
[phone rings]
- Nixie speaking.
[电话铃声]
- 尼克西讲话。
- Nixie! My bestest friend
in the whole wide world.
- 尼克西！我最好的朋友
在整个世界。
You should come over.
你应该过来。
We can watch TV
and eat cheese!
我们可以看电视
并吃奶酪！
- I wish I could, Pearl,
- 我希望我可以，珍珠，
but I have to work
at Dangles and Bangles.
但我必须工作
在吊坠和手镯。
All dangles are half off with
the purchase of any bangle.
所有吊坠均半价
购买任何手镯。
Dangle must be of equal
or lesser value than bangle.
悬垂必须相等
或价值低于手镯。
Some restrictions may apply.
可能存在一些限制。
- Oh, you don't work
at the mall, do you, Derek?
-哦，你不工作
德里克，你在商场吗？
- No, but all my girlfriends do.
- 不，但我所有的女朋友都这样。
[ding]
[叮]
- Daddy!
Guess what?
- 爸爸！
你猜怎么着？
- [gasps]
- [喘气]
[muttering frantically]
[疯狂地嘀咕]
[chuckles]
I have no idea, Pearly.
[笑声]
我不知道，珀莉。
- Dad, I'm getting a job today.
- 爸爸，我今天找到工作了。
- [shouts]
- [喊叫]
Yahoo!
雅虎！
Oh, this is great news,
Pearl, me dear!
哦，这是个好消息，
珍珠，亲爱的！
Now instead of wasting
my precious money
现在而不是浪费
我的宝贵金钱
on your "clothes"
and your "school supplies"...
在你的“衣服”上
还有你的“学习用品”...
[chuckles]
You can waste your own.
[笑声]
你可以浪费你自己的。
- I'll be a independent
working woman,
- 我会成为一个独立的人
职业女性，
blazing my own trail and
standing on my own two fins.
开辟自己的道路并
靠自己的两个鳍站立。
- That's the spirit.
- 这就是精神。
- Oh, can I borrow $10?
- 哦，我可以借 10 美元吗？
[cash register chimes]
[收银机铃声]
- I'll miss you
around the house.
- 我会想念你的
房子周围。
- Oh, Daddy, you'll see me
after work.
- 哦，爸爸，你会看到我的
下班后。
- I was talkin' to the money.
- 我是在和钱说话。
- Hey, Marina!
- 嘿，玛丽娜！
I'm here to apply for a job.
我来这里是为了申请工作。
- You should meet the manager,
I guess?
- 你应该见见经理
我猜？
He's in his office.
他在他的办公室里。
Mr. Pepalino, there's someone
here for a job.
佩帕利诺先生，有人
来这里找工作。
- Ah!
- 啊！
- [straining]
- [紧张]
- [grunting and groaning]
- [咕哝和呻吟]
I-I don't think he's in there.
我-我不认为他在里面。
- [muffled moaning]
- [低沉的呻吟声]
[mumbling]
[咕哝]
[groaning]
[呻吟]
[gargling]
[漱口]
[steam hissing]
[蒸汽嘶嘶声]
We're not hiring.
我们不招聘。
[heavy metal guitar tones]
[重金属吉他音色]
- Welcome to Scorched Coral.
Please go away.
- 欢迎来到焦珊瑚。
请走开。
Oh, hey, Pearl.
What are you doing here?
哦，嘿，珀尔。
你在这里做什么？
- I would like to apply
for a job, please.
- 我想申请
为了一份工作，请。
- Yeah, sorry.
You're a little late.
- 是的，抱歉。
你来晚了一点。
We were hiring, but we actually
just hired someone today.
我们正在招聘，但实际上我们
今天刚雇了一个人。
- [hissing and growling]
- [嘶嘶声和咆哮声]
- Ah!
- 啊！
Oh, Nixie, I need to work
at Dangles and Bangles.
哦，尼克西，我需要工作
在吊坠和手镯。
This is my last chance.
You gotta help me out here.
这是我最后的机会了。
你得帮我一下。
Oh, please, please, please,
please, please!
哦，拜托，拜托，拜托，
拜托，拜托！
- Come on, let me introduce you
to the manager.
- 来吧，我给你介绍一下
给经理。
- This is--
- Nope, not hiring.
- 这是--
- 不，不是招聘。
- You don't understand.
I have to work here!
- 你不明白。
我必须在这里工作！
- Sorry, missy, the only thing
we don't dangle here
- 对不起，小姐，唯一的事情
我们不在这里晃荡
is hope.
是希望。
- Oh, bangles.
- 哦，手镯。
[tropical music]
[热带音乐]
Ah...
啊...
[belches]
[打嗝]
Oh, this is the worst.
哦，这是最糟糕的。
If I don't get a job
at the mall,
如果我找不到工作
在商场，
I'm gonna have to hang out
with my dad.
我得出去玩
和我爸爸。
[sighs]
[叹气]
- You looking for a job,
deary?
- 你正在寻找工作，
亲爱的？
- Yeah!
I need one as soon as possible.
- 是的！
我尽快需要一个。
It's a life or death situation,
actually.
这是生死攸关的情况
实际上。
- Oh, my goodness.
- 哦，我的天啊。
Are you in danger?
你有危险吗？
- In danger
of never seeing my friends
- 处于危险之中
从未见过我的朋友
'cause I don't have a job.
因为我没有工作。
- Come with me.
- 跟我来。
[glass shattering]
[玻璃破碎]
- [gasps]
Weird.
- [喘气]
奇怪。
[alarm blaring]
[whistle blowing]
[警报声]
[吹口哨]
I've never been in this part
of the mall before.
我从来没有参与过这部分
之前的商场。
[gasps]
Ugh!
[喘气]
呃！
What's that smell?
那是什么味道？
- Oh, probably one of the many
perfumes that we sell
- 哦，可能是众多之一
我们销售的香水
here at Grandma's Apron!
这里是奶奶的围裙！
Congratulations!
You're hired.
恭喜！
你被录用了。
- [gasps]
- [喘气]
Oh, this is the best day
of my life!
哦，这是最好的一天
我的生活！
- [groaning]
- [呻吟]
Ah!
[back pops]
啊!
[回弹]
Well, I can't quite afford
to be picky these days.
好吧，我买不起
这些天变得挑剔。
The only other employee
besides me was Myrtle,
唯一的另一名员工
除了我之外还有默特尔，
and she's...no longer with us.
她……不再和我们在一起了。
- [shrieks]
Almost forgot my shades!
- [尖叫]
差点忘记我的墨镜了！
See ya later, suckers!
待会儿见，傻瓜们！
[laughing]
[笑]
- Hey, Pearl.
Over here.
- 嘿，珀尔。
在这里。
- Did you find a job?
- 你找到工作了吗？
- Yeah, I got a job
at Grandma's Apron.
- 是的，我找到了工作
在奶奶的围裙处。
- [laughing]
Pearl, you can not be serious.
- [笑]
珍珠，你不是认真的吧。
- Ew, that store is
for old people.
- 呃，那家商店是
对于老人来说。
- [laughing]
Old people are so...old.
- [笑]
老人们都这么……老了。
- Old people aren't that bad.
- 老年人没那么坏。
Are they?
他们是吗？
- [mumbling]
- [咕哝]
- [slurping]
- [发出声音]
[laughter]
[笑声]
[ragtime music]
[拉格泰姆音乐]
*
- Hey, girls,
I smell moth balls.
- 嘿，女孩们，
我闻到了樟脑丸的味道。
- Well, we are having a sale
on them.
- 嗯，我们正在促销
在他们身上。
They're 25% off today.
今天他们有 25% 的折扣。
- Um, isn't it
your nap time, Pearl?
- 嗯，不是吗
你午睡时间到了吗，珀尔？
- Where's your muumuu, granny?
- 你的muumuu在哪里，奶奶？
[laughter]
[笑声]
- Oh, don't let those
bubble-headed nincompoops
- 哦，别让那些
泡泡头傻瓜
get to you, Pearly.
去找你，珀莉。
- But it's not fair.
- 但这不公平。
- Life's not fair, my dear.
- 生活是不公平的，亲爱的。
We all go through hard times
at some point.
我们都会经历困难时期
在某个时刻。
Here, look.
See?
在这里，看。
看？
I was different
from the other girls,
我是不同的
从其他女孩那里，
and they teased me for it.
他们因此取笑我。
They called me
"Boring Beatrice."
他们打电话给我
“无聊的贝阿特丽斯。”
Not very creative, those girls.
[chuckles]
那些女孩们不太有创意。
[笑声]
- Who would even
take a picture of that?
- 谁会甚至
拍张照片吗？
- Oh, good ol' Jonesy
from the AV Club took that one!
- 噢，好样的琼斯
从 AV 俱乐部拿走了那一张！
- Wait, but who took
that picture--
- 等等，但是谁拿走了
那张照片——
- All that matters,
Pearly, my dear,
- 重要的是，
珍珠般的，亲爱的，
is that things will soon change.
事情很快就会改变。
But in the meantime,
但与此同时，
you should be having
as much fun as possible.
你应该有
尽可能多的乐趣。
Let me show you
how grandmas do it.
让我告诉你
奶奶们是怎么做的。
[jazz music]
[爵士乐]
*
[explosion]
[爆炸]
*
[laughter]
[笑声]
*
- Whoa, come back here, yarn!
- 哇哦，回来吧，纱线！
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
[all gasp]
[全都喘气]
[dramatic tones]
[戏剧性的语气]
- [laughing]
Love the shoes, Pearl.
- [笑]
喜欢这双鞋，珍珠。
- You guys just don't get it.
=> - 你们只是不明白。
Being a grandma is fun.
当奶奶很有趣。
I get to sit
in a rocking chair,
我可以坐下来
坐在摇椅上，
dust tchotchkes,
灰尘小玩意，
bake cookies,
烤饼干，
knit mittens,
hats, and scarves.
针织手套，
帽子、围巾。
[laughter]
[笑声]
- Scarves.
- 围巾。
- It's actually, like, the most
coral store in the whole mall,
- 这实际上是最
整个商场的珊瑚店，
so you can all just...just...
eat barnacles!
所以你们都可以只是...只是...
吃藤壶！
[laughter]
[笑声]
- Now, now, girls.
Let's be polite.
- 现在，现在，女孩们。
我们要有礼貌。
- What are you gonna do
about it, granny?
-你要做什么
关于这件事，奶奶？
[grunting menacingly]
[威胁地咕哝]
- Granny power!
- 奶奶的力量！
[echoing]
Power! Power!
[回声]
力量！力量！
- Aah!
- 啊啊！
- [growls]
- [咆哮]
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
- Aah!
- 啊啊！
[all screaming]
[所有人尖叫]
- Pearl, toss me
the Autumn Years perfume.
- 珍珠，扔给我吧
秋季香水。
- Hi-ya!
- 嗨呀！
*
[all screaming]
[所有人尖叫]
- It smells like pills
and bed pans.
- 闻起来像药丸
和便盆。
Whoa!
哇！
*
- [laughing]
- [笑]
*
[all whimpering]
[全都呜咽]
- Well, now that
you're all sitting down,
- 好吧，现在
你们都坐下了
let me tell you
about the first time
让我告诉你
关于第一次
I ever saw a talking
picture show.
我曾经见过一个会说话的人
图片展示。
Oh, boy, did they know
how to talk.
哦，天哪，他们知道吗
怎样说话。
- No, please!
I can't take any more!
- 不，拜托！
我再也受不了了！
- It's... so...boring.
- 这……太……无聊了。
- No, I hate the past.
- 不，我讨厌过去。
- And that's why today,
we all wear shoes.
- 这就是为什么今天，
我们都穿鞋。
- Okay, okay,
We get it.
- 好吧，好吧，
我们明白了。
We will stop being mean,
I promise.
我们将不再卑鄙，
我保证。
Just let us go.
让我们走吧。
all: Whoa!
全体：哇！
[all groaning]
[全都呻吟]
- Listen, Pearl.
- 听着，珀尔。
We didn't mean to hurt
your feeling or anything.
我们无意伤害
你的感觉或者什么。
We just, like, think it's weird
that you're, like,
我们只是觉得这很奇怪
你就像
a grandma now or whatever.
现在已经是奶奶了或者什么的。
We don't really get it.
我们真的不明白。
- Well, I don't care
what you think anymore anyway.
- 好吧，我不在乎
无论如何，你怎么想？
I'm being true to myself,
我忠于自己，
and--and that's all
that matters!
以及——仅此而已
这很重要！
all: Eh.
全体：呃。
- I'm a grandma now.
Right, Beatrice?
- 我现在是奶奶了。
对吧，比阿特丽斯？
- Oh, Pearl, I'm so glad
you enjoy being a grandma,
- 哦，珍珠，我很高兴
你享受当奶奶的乐趣
but your friends
make a good point.
但你的朋友
提出一个好观点。
You're only young once, you see.
你知道，你的青春只有一次。
You don't want
to grow up too fast
你不想要
成长得太快
or you'll miss out
on all the fun.
否则你会错过
一切的乐趣。
- I guess you're right.
- 我想你是对的。
Being a grandma is nice and all,
当奶奶真是太好了
but I do miss
being a super hip young person.
但我确实想念
是一个超级时髦的年轻人。
- Go have yourself some fun,
my dear.
- 去玩玩吧
亲爱的。
Ah, ah, ah, ah.
啊啊啊啊啊。
How 'bout a nice,
gentle handshake instead?
怎么样一个漂亮的，
而是温柔地握手？
[groans]
- Hey, wait up, guys!
[呻吟]
- 嘿，等等，伙计们！
I want to be friends
while I'm still young!
我想成为朋友
趁我还年轻！
- I'll see you tomorrow.
- 明天见。
- You dropped this.
- 你把这个掉了。